They managed to get in...
Diting couldn't defeat them?
They aren't strong. They just copied themselves, and Diting fell for it.
But you can drive them away easily, can't you?
I can't leave this place for a hundred years.
Or get involved with outside affairs.
Doesn't "this place" mean Blue Creek?
It's not even the mountain. I must stay in the tower.
How many years are left?
Sixty, seventy.
You make your own life harder.
If you help drive them away,
I'll help you get your real form back as a reward.
Deal!
Which way?
Straight ahead is Mount Laojun.
That way, the Grand Dipper Palace.
That way, the Imperial Lockup Palace.
We go there.
Blue Creek
Do you like it?
Hi, Laozi.
Where's Gen?
I sent them to run an errand.
Let's work together now!
Sure!
I'll sign with my eyes.
It's too hard...
Why is it that we always have to wait at doors?
Is this the place?
There's nothing here.
There's a hole, isn't there?
Don't tell me this is the Imperial Lockup Palace.
Just get inside first.
Even if Laozi doesn't intervene,
you can't seal his realm for long.
Get on with it!
This way!
You like that magazine too?
I also love it.
ONLY comes next week, wanna go?
I can't go out.
No good?
This seal is rather complicated.
It can take a long time.
May I ask you to leave?
How come someone else is here?
What do we do?
We must fight!
Ice magic!
Space magic?!
What were you like at 10?
I can't remember.
That space magic is quite troublesome!
But it requires a magical artifact.
They can return instantly to where the artifact is.
While attacking, pay attention to the movement of the artifact!
Things I usually do?
Read books, prepare the elixir of immortality, surf the internet...
Does the Jade Emperor exist?
No.
What about the heavenly court?
Also no.
Then the myths are not true?
Some of them are.
We can't make noise inside a temple! Come back!
Okay.
Does Sun Wukong exist?
Yes.
Really? Is he super strong?
Not that strong.
Isn't he the Great Sage Equal to Heaven?
That's only in the novel.
You read Journey to the West?
When it was first published.
Watch out!
Are you okay?
Water would have been better...
You have no eyebrows.
You have no nose.
It's a deadlock. He has the advantage.
We must use the Firestorm!
Our last resort...
Darn all this teleportation!
They try to use the Firestorm?
Come here!
He absorbed it!
How is this possible?
It should cancel ice magic!
Is it you...
Lord Xuanli?
You flatter me.
You're quite famous.
Another spirit beast! We have no chance.
Excuse our intrusion.
We are leaving now.
Thank you.
Are we really...?
Let's go.
Is your name that effective?
I don't think so, they tricked Diting too.
Follow them!
Where's the restroom?
There's none.
How come?
Ever seen an immortal use the toilet?
Mm...
Don't you trust us?
It's part of my job.
Leave now.
I need to ask for your forgiveness again.
We will apologize after it happened.
Darn!
I've messed it up.
They fell for the same as Diting.
Xiaobai is outside!
What? Why did she go outside?
To pee...
There's another entrance we can use!
Follow me!
Much better!
Xiaohei, what's wrong?
Another person?
Is this a side-scrolling game?
No one told us about this!
I'll stop her. You go on!
Hope she's no spirit beast!
Oh, no!
Take my spirit part back!
Xiaohei?
Collection of Twelve
I think this is a human!
What?
He's so fast!
Well, you came just in time!
Now you look even less like a cat.
Is Xiaobai all right?
Yes.
Gen!
Xiaobai!
Here's our chance!
There's no chance.
What the...?!
Still want to fight?
We surrender, we really do.
Summer must be cool with you.
Why did you come here?
Laozi once said,
that whoever forces him to attack,
will get the Pure Black Elixir.
Book of Vows
Did I say that?
Then why did you want to break into the palace?
Laozi once said,
that whoever breaks into the palace,
will get the Green Soul Fruit.
You must be quite lonely...
Book of Vows
A Soul Calling Stone.
Please accept it. I hope you can forgive us.
It's all because of Master Lao's vow book.
It's me who should ask for your forgiveness.
You're being too kind.
Are we allowed to leave now?
Of course.
You can go.
We are grateful.
Are they bad guys?
I don't know.
Xiaohei...
Is Xiaohei too a spirit?
Did he scare you?
I know he only wanted to protect me.
What happened to him?
He just got a little weak.
Like Piyu, after he transforms.
So Piyu's a spirit too?
No.
It's the anatomy of the dumpling mouse.
What's wrong?
If Piyu transformed in the forest...
I couldn't help him.
Do you miss him much?
But he's home now.
He must be very happy.
Is he all right?
He forced himself to transform.
Inflicted wounds upon wounds.
What? Is it that serious?
Not particularly.
But he'll lose some years of cultivation.
Say his old wounds made him lose HP.
Then this one reduced his HP gauge.
What?
With my abilities,
I can only help him slowly recover.
After all, I'm not a healer.
I think you are.
Year 13 of Wuxian
239.
The one who hunts
the White-Feathered Silkie
will get
the Silk Phoenix Elixir
237.
Those who collect the inscriptions
from all the memorial arches in town
will get
the Black Gold Elixir
238.
Those who beat me three times
in a row in five-in-a-row
will get
a Laozi statue
All right.
Is he healed?
Of course not.
It will take about a month.
Then he must stay here with you?
No.
I'll give the cure to you.
You can take care of him at home.
Why had you made so many vows?
Because I'm so lonely!
Immortal life must be really boring...
But I made even my latest vows many decades ago.
No wonder even I forgot about them.
And recently?
Now I've got company.
You mean Diting?
I mean the internet.
I know.
Don't you know a certain Fairy Qingning?
That's just...
a wishful thought of mine.
She didn't go out with you?
None of your business.
Aren't you an immortal?
What's so great about it?
Were you always an immortal?
It's just a title.
Actually, I'm a kind of spirit too.
What? Really?
If they master the powers of nature,
any sentient being can attain the title of god.
So even a human can become a god?
Sure, even the mightiest god of the present era was once a human.
Really?
Wow...
Xiaobai's worldview
Back up
Refresh
Rebuild
Deac-
tivate
Back up
Refresh
But he was born hundreds of years ago.
People of today have lost the connection to the powers of nature.
But if you ask, who are
the mightiest beings of all time,
it may well be that people of today are.
I've digressed.
It's getting rather late.
I should send you home now.
Can I visit you again someday?
I can bring you anime merchandise!
Sure!
I give this Blue Jade Disc to you.
Let it be the seal of our friendship.
Are you sure? Isn't this a...?
It's fine.
The old man's in a good mood.
And what's this for?
You can come here with it.
Xuanli will show you how.
Thanks, Laozi!
I'll visit you often.
Just don't lose it.
Master, we have to say goodbye now.
Bye!
There we are.
We teleported!
It has a cool-down time.
Don't overuse it.
Are we... in the mountains?
Yes.
The house is still flooded,
so we came here first.
Gen...
Do you think Piyu already made friends?
Maybe.
But there are few dumpling mice left.
What if he can't find others?
Don't worry, he feels good here in the forest.
Okay then...
But if he happened to be lonely...
Then...
can we take him home?
The forest is his home.
Laozi is at home all the time.
Still, he's bored to death.
Aren't you afraid?
You and Xiaohei will protect me.
And I will protect Piyu and Xiaohei.
Right.
I'm sure you will be a good owner to Piyu.
He's still waiting for you at the border stone.
Really?
Let's go for him!
Careful!
Piyu!
Open it already...
You don't know how to face Xiaobai, right?
Shut up.
Don't you worry about her?
I do.
But...
Their feelings for each other...
are worth to be cherished.
Don't get lost again!
You want me to leave here?
This is your wish?
Yes.
It goes against the vow I've made earlier.
I'm sorry, but I can't do that.
If he's not willing,
don't push it.
Just take the Pearl.
Then I take the Pearl.
I suppose this wasn't your idea.
Wuxian sent you, right?
Thank him for me.
Xiaobai?
I can understand him!
How's this possible?
It's a form of telepathy.
How weird!
So others can't hear you?
No, I decide who I talk to.
This is so very very cool!
Next time I have an exam, you sit under the window and tell me the answers!
It's not meant for that...
You got used to it quick.
Spirit force
Xiaohei, how's your wound?
It's all right.
Grandpa!
Welcome back!
You brought Piyu too?
Please don't eat the house :'(
Hi, Uncle San!
When
When did
When did you
When did you come
When did you come back?
Four days ago.
I
I se
I see
I seee
I seeee
I seeeee!
Just four days?
Why does it seem longer to me?
Because the software update took long?
Never mind.
So Xiaohei is a spirit too!
Nice to meet you.
You can call me Lil Bro Luo from now on.
I'm still the younger one...
Before I forget.
Laozi sent you this.
Hoho, the money's here!
Don't do this again.
Got no money
Can I demolish the village Laozi temple?
I'm sick of you two...
What's this?
Got no money
Go to this place
Looks like a map.
Let me see.
It's in the city.
So he wants us to go there?
What if it's a trap?
No way.
Xiaobai! We cook dinner, you can take a bath first.
Sure.
It's so beautiful!
It's like the sea.
Yeah.
In a few days it will be gone.
Luckily, the harvest is already over.
Tomorrow we'll start training Piyu about what he can eat.
Piyu, be a good boy!
If Piyu's not a spirit,
how come he can turn into a giant?
"Spirit" is a name for a certain kind of lifeform.
But not only they can control spirit force.
In theory, all living things can do it.
You're right.
Laozi said too that a human can become god.
So even I could control water like you?
Sure.
Really?
And how?
You're interested?
Everywhere around us
there's a legion of invisible beings,
filling up space.
There are material sprites and soulful sprites.
Soulful sprites can merge,
and become bodiless fairies.
They keep changing, absorbing more sprites,
then combine with material sprites,
and so become beings with bodies.
These are called spirits.
As they are born from sprites,
they're naturally better at controlling spirit force.
You remember Master Lao's realm?
Spirit space is the key to spirit force.
By cultivation, attributes of the spirit space can be changed.
And those who have no spirit space, they can't even do that?
Every living thing has one.
We absorb sprites with every breath.
Then how come I don't know any other person like you?
It all depends on innate properties.
Here.
Wow, cool!
If a human spends decades with mastering ice magic,
this is the level they can reach.
But an ice type spirit
is capable of much more from its birth.
So even in old times, few people cultivated.
Not to mention modern times.
But didn't Laozi say today's mightiest god had been a human?
He did. I talk about ordinary people.
Of course, there are always naturals.
The skills depend on the size of the spirit space.
An ordinary person has one about the size of a basketball.
What about yours?
Now it's about...
the size of a soccer field.
Is it beautiful too?
Not at all.
You'd freeze to death in mine.
It's an icy hell.
And how big is Laozi's space?
We didn't see all of it, or?
In fact it's just the size of Blue Creek.
What about Mt. Laojun?
Isn't it in the space?
On the back of Blue Creek.
What?!
Imagine the spirit space is a sphere.
Blue Creek is in one side of the sphere.
Under it is Starry Night Lake.
Mt. Laojun is here.
Inbetween, the four palaces.
By the physical laws defined by Master Lao,
each has its own direction of gravity.
Xiaobai's worldview
Back up
Refresh
Rebuild
Deac-
tivate
Xiaobai's worldview
Back up
Refresh
Rebuild
Deac-
tivate
Xiaobai's worldview
Back up
Refresh
Rebuild
Deac-
tivate
I see...
Why did you eat it?
Now I'm a babysitter...
I was wondering.
Xiaohei, what's your power?
You'll see when I'm cured.
Then be healthy soon!
Next, we'll cover spirit force and subspace abilities in the spirit space.
I can't follow you anymore...
Then I'll continue slower.
These summer nights are so nice!
Yeah.
With Master Lao's cure, you'll recover in a month.
Will you leave here then?
I don't know...
It's fine not to know.
You have time to decide.
But some troubles may come to you...
What troubles?
Don't you know?
The Sky Pearl invites trouble.
Go!
Somebody's coming.
What are these?
Stay with me aruite yukou ishikoro wo kette
Stay with me - let's walk on, kicking pebbles as we go
Yukisaki wa kitto kimagure demo
Our destination may be whimsical
Hana no kaori wo ryoute ni
But with the scent of flowers in both hands
kore kara deau kimi e to
I’ll carry it to the you I’ve yet to meet
Wait for me hanashi wo shiyou kata wo narabete
Wait for me — let’s talk, side by side
Hajimemashite wa gikochinaku temo
Even if our first “hello” is a little awkward
Mochiyotta hako aketara
When we open the boxes we’ve brought
Tsumekon da yume wo wakeaou
Let’s share the dreams we’ve packed inside
Mata ashita tte atarimae ni kawaseru hibi ga
The days when we can casually say “See you tomorrow”
Itoshikute hakanasugite
Are so precious and so fleeting
Omoi wa kitto kienai
Those feelings will never fade away
Sora wo nagareru kumo ni wa oitsukenai kedo
We can’t catch up to the clouds drifting across the sky
Ame ni natte hana wo tsukete kitto boku wo yonderu
But they’ll turn to rain, bloom into flowers
Kitto boku wo yonderu
And surely, they’re calling out to me